Guide to the Katherine S. Dreier Papers / Societe Anonyme Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Katherine S. Dreier: Writings, 1891-1951; Series II; 6; (17 boxes)
  - LECTURES
    - [Art as pertaining to life], typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1324)
      At Heterodoxy Club.
    - "Art as Seen by a Modernist," typescript and carbon, corrected, 1928 Feb 25 (Box 45, Folder 1325)
      At Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.). Includes advertisements.
    - "Art in Relation to Life," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 45, Folder 1326)
    - "Art in the Twentieth Century," clippings of announcements, 1930 Oct (Box 45, Folder 1327)
      At Rand School of Social Science.
    - "The Average Man's Reaction to Various Art Forms," typescript, corrected, 1933 Nov 16 (Box 45, Folder 1328)
    - "The Balance of Work and Play in Life," typescript, corrected (Box 45, Folder 1329)
    - "Cézanne and His Group," typescript, corrected, 1930 Dec 2 (Box 45, Folder 1330)
      At Rand School of Social Science. Includes program.
    - [Charity to Germany and Austria], typescript carbon (Box 45, Folder 1331)
    - "Chicago and the Century of Progress," typescript carbon (Box 45, Folder 1332)
      List of slides.
    - [Chinese Pictures], typescript, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1333)
    - "Christmas in Various Lands," typescript, 1948 Dec 2 (Box 45, Folder 1334)
      At Daughters of the American Revolution, Milford Chapter (Milford, Conn.).
    - [Comparative history of art], notes, holograph, and draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1925 Nov 20 (Box 45, Folder 1335)
      At Mount Vernon Seminary.
    - [Concept of space in modern art], typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1336)
      At Women's University Club.
    - [Confucius], typescript, corrected, 1935 Nov (Box 45, Folder 1337)
      At Black Mountain College (Black Mountain, N.C.).
    - [Contribution of modern artists], typescript and carbon, corrected, 1925 Mar 27 (Box 45, Folder 1338)
    - "The Creative Urge - and Its Expression in Art Forms," typescript, corrected, 1933 Nov 9 (Box 45, Folder 1339)
      At Academy of Allied Arts.
    - "The Current Exhibition of International Modern Art," typescript carbon, corrected, 1926 Nov 28 (Box 45, Folder 1340)
      At Brooklyn Museum. Includes invitation; program.
    - "The Difference Between Art and Taste," typescript carbon, corrected, 1930 Nov 18 (Box 45, Folder 1341)
      Includes clipping.
    - "The Difference Between Art and Taste," typescript and carbon, 1933 Nov 23 (Box 45, Folder 1342)
    - "The Difference Between - Fashion - Taste - and Art," typescript and carbon, 1935 Jun 17 (Box 45, Folder 1343)
      At Annot Art School. Includes invitation; clipping.
    - "The Difference Between - Fashion - Taste - and Art," drafts, typescript carbon, 1935 Oct 25 (Box 45, Folder 1344)
      At Connecticut Art Association. Includes review of lecture, Connecticut Teacher, 1935 Dec.
    - "Dr. Walter Reed," typescript, corrected, 1927 Jul 6 (Box 45, Folder 1345)
      At Long Ridge Women's Club (West Redding, Conn.).
    - "Does 'Self Expression in Art' Create Art Appreciation, corrected, 1933 Nov 28 (Box 45, Folder 1346)
    - "Dynamic Imagination," typescript and carbon, corrected, 1933 Dec 7 (Box 45, Folder 1347)
    - "An Evening with the Art of the Future"
      - Sponsored by the SA at the New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.).
      - Address by KSD, typescript, corrected, 1931 Mar 23 (Box 45, Folder 1348)
      - Invitation, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1349)
      - Ticket, n.d.
      - Program, drafts, typescript, corrected and printed version, 1931
      - Lists of patronesses, 1931
      - Notes on expenses, n.d.
      - Clippings, 1931-32
    - "Famous American Woman Painters," typescript carbon, corrected, 1941 Aug 12 (Box 46, Folder 1350)
    - "The Father, by August Strindberg," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 46, Folder 1351)
    - [Florentine paintings], holograph, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1352)
    - "From El Greco to Kandinsky," typescript and carbon, corrected, 1933 Dec 14 (Box 46, Folder 1353)
    - "From What Angle Do We Approach Art," typescript, corrected, 1931 Jan 12 (Box 46, Folder 1354)
      At New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.).
    - [From what angle do we approach this exhibition?...], typescript, 1931 Feb 2 (Box 46, Folder 1355)
    - [Fundamental principles in modern art], typescript, 1926 Jan 28 (Box 46, Folder 1356)
      At Painters and Sculptors Gallery (New York, N.Y.).
    - "Fundamentals in Art," drafts, typescript, holograph, and carbon, corrected, 1931 Jan 5 (Box 46, Folder 1357-1359)
      At New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.). Includes announcement; program; clippings.
    - [German Home for Recreation of Women and Children membership appeal], typescript carbon (Box 46, Folder 1360)
    - "Germany," drafts, typescript, corrected, 1933 Jun 7 (Box 46, Folder 1361)
    - "Good Art and Good...Taste - Are They the Same?," typescript carbon, corrected, [1938 Mar 15] (Box 46, Folder 1362)
      At Columbia University. Includes invitation.
    - "The Growing Emphasis on Gardens," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1363)
    - "The Home and Its Changes," typescript, corrected, 1930 Oct 28 (Box 46, Folder 1364)
    - "How to Build a Picture," typescript, corrected, 1931 Jan 19 (Box 46, Folder 1365)
    - [Illustrations for a lecture], typescript carbon (2 copies), n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1366)
    - [International Exhibition of Modern Art (1926-1927: Brooklyn Museum)], typescript carbon, 1926 Nov 20 (Box 46, Folder 1367)
      At Brooklyn Museum; for School Art League.
    - [International Exhibition of Modern Art (1926-1927: Brooklyn Museum)], typescript carbon, 1926 Dec 15 (Box 46, Folder 1368)
      At Brooklyn Museum; for Civitas Club.
    - [International Exhibition of Modern Art (1926-1927: Brooklyn Museum)], drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1927 Jan 28 (Box 46, Folder 1369)
      At Brooklyn Museum.
    - [International Exhibition of Modern Art (1926-1927: Brooklyn Museum). Rationale], typescript carbon (fragment), n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1370)
    - "'Intrinsic Significance' in Modern Art," typescript, carbon, and mimeograph, corrected, 1948 Mar 5 (Box 46, Folder 1371)
      Includes questions and answers, typescript carbon, corrected.
    - [Introduction to Henry McBride's lecture on humor in modern art], typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1372)
    - "Kandinsky and His Contribution," typescript, corrected, 1931 Mar 9 (Box 46, Folder 1373)
    - [Kandinsky's contribution to art], typescript and carbon, corrected, 1930 Aug 7 (Box 46, Folder 1374)
      At Darien Guild of Seven Arts (Darien, Conn.). Includes clipping.
    - "Life and the Now," typescript, corrected, 1946 Nov 1 (Box 46, Folder 1375)
      At Hartford Seminary Foundation. Includes exhibition catalog.
    - "The Madonna in Art," typescript and carbon, corrected, 1935 Sep 6 (Box 46, Folder 1376)
      At Long Ridge Methodist Episcopal Church (West Redding, Conn.).
    - "A Message from the Past: Pierce - Buchanan - Lincoln, 1853-1865," typescript, corrected, 1940 Oct 5 (Box 46, Folder 1377)
    - "Modern Architecture Here and Abroad," typescript, corrected, 1930 Dec 7 (Box 47, Folder 1378)
      At Brooklyn Museum. Includes program.
    - [Modern art], drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1927 Jan 24 (Box 47, Folder 1379)
      Radio talk via National Broadcasting Company.
      See also: Box 25, folder 746
    - [Modern art], typescript carbon, corrected, 1927 Jan 28 (Box 47, Folder 1380)
    - [Modern art], typescript, corrected, 1927 Feb 28 (Box 47, Folder 1381)
      At Albright Art Gallery (Buffalo, N.Y.).
    - [Modern art], typescript carbon, 1927 Mar 10 (Box 47, Folder 1382)
      At Women's Club, Rye (N.Y.).
    - [Modern art], typescript carbon, 1927 Mar 15 (Box 47, Folder 1383)
      At Cosmopolitan Club, New York.
      See also: Box 41, folder 1240
      See also: Box 47, folder 1386
    - [Modern art], typescript carbon, 1927 Mar 17 (Box 47, Folder 1384)
      "Before the Art Teachers of the Primary and Lower High School Classes."
    - [Modern art], typescript carbon and printed version, 1927 Apr 4 (Box 47, Folder 1385)
      In Toronto.
    - [Modern art], typescript carbon, 1927 May 12 (Box 47, Folder 1386)
      "Before the Art Teachers of the High Schools of the City of New York..."
    - [Modern art], drafts, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1927 (Box 47, Folder 1387)
      At "A Section of the International Exhibition," at Anderson Galleries.
    - [Modern art as new expression], typescript carbon, corrected, 1925 Mar 25 (Box 47, Folder 1388)
      At 88 Central Park West.
      See also: Box 45, folder 1338
      See also: Box 49, folder 1438
    - [Modern contribution to art], typescript carbon, corrected, 1929 Aug 25 (Box 47, Folder 1389)
      In Darien (Conn.).
    - "The Need of Art, Music, and Drama in the Life of Youth," typescript, corrected, [1930 Dec 2] (Box 47, Folder 1390)
      At Cosmopolitan Club; for New York League for Mental Hygiene of Children Includes invitation and brochure.
    - "The Negro in the Educational World," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1391)
    - [New forms in art], typescript, corrected, 1935 Jun 10 (Box 47, Folder 1392)
      At Methodist Episcopal Church (Bethel, Conn.).
    - "New Forms in Painting," drafts, typescript, corrected, 1930 Dec 16 (Box 47, Folder 1393)
      At Rand School of Social Science. Includes invitation; program.
    - "New Orleans," typescript carbon, corrected, 1930 Jul 30 (Box 47, Folder 1394)
    - [Opening of exhibition sponsored by Société Anonyme], typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1395)
    - "Our Changing Geography: China and Ourselves," typescript, corrected, 1942 (Box 47, Folder 1396)
      See also: Box 41, folder 1225
    - "Our Imagination and How to Use Our Eyes," typescript, corrected, 1930 Nov 25 (Box 47, Folder 1397)
    - "Painting," typescript carbon, corrected, 1946 Oct 1 (Box 47, Folder 1398)
    - "Painting in 1900," typescript, corrected, 1930 Oct 14 (Box 47, Folder 1399)
    - "The Panama Canal," draft, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1929 Sep 11 (Box 47, Folder 1400)
    - [Patriotic education in Little Italy (Brooklyn, N.Y.)], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1401)
    - "Pictures of Chinese Life," typescript carbon, corrected, 1933 Nov 19 (Box 47, Folder 1402)
      At Panhellenic. Includes program.
    - "Pierce through Lincoln, 1853-1865," typescript carbon, corrected, 1940 Jul 16 (Box 47, Folder 1403)
      At Long Ridge Women's Club (West Redding, Conn.). Includes program.
    - "Pioneers in Sociology," drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, 1941 Jul 15 (Box 47, Folder 1404)
    - "The Place of the Abstract in Art," typescript carbon, corrected, 1931 Mar 16 (Box 47, Folder 1405)
    - "Present Day American Tendencies," typescript carbon, corrected, 1931 Feb 9 (Box 47, Folder 1406)
    - "Present Day Art Tendencies and Their Roots," typescript carbon, corrected, 1931 Jan 26 (Box 47, Folder 1407)
      At New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.). Includes clipping.
    - "Present Day French Tendencies," typescript carbon, corrected, 1931 Feb 16 (Box 47, Folder 1408)
    - "Present Day German Tendencies," typescript carbon, corrected, 1931 Mar 2 (Box 47, Folder 1409)
    - "Present Day Russian Tendencies," typescript carbon, corrected, 1931 Feb 23 (Box 47, Folder 1410)
    - "The Progress in Art in the Last Twenty Years, drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 47, Folder 1411)
    - [Radio talks on art], notes, holograph and drafts, typescript, corrected (Box 48, Folder 1412)
      Twelve talks.
      See also: Oversize, box 118, folder 2805
    - "The Rebels in Art of Our Times," drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, [1921 Jan 15?] (Box 48, Folder 1413)
      At Manhattan Trade School. Includes program.
    - "The Revolt of 1911-13," typescript, corrected, 1930 Dec 9 (Box 48, Folder 1414)
    - "The Revolution in Art," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1415)
      For League for Industrial Democracy, at Civic Club (New York, N.Y.). Includes program.
    - "Sacred Music," notes, holograph, and draft, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1939 Jun 20 (Box 48, Folder 1416)
    - "Should Art be a Part of Every Day Life," typescript, corrected, 1933 Dec 21 (Box 48, Folder 1417)
    - "Should Art be a Part of Every Day Life?," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1934 Feb 4 (Box 48, Folder 1418-1419)
      At Panhellenic. Includes clipping.
    - "Some Reflections on China," drafts, typescript carbon, 1947 Nov 17 (Box 48, Folder 1420)
      At Historical Society of Milford.
    - "Some Things I Learned in and about China," typescript, 1926 Feb 28 (Box 48, Folder 1421)
      At Brooklyn Museum. Includes clippings.
    - [Space and time], typescript carbon, corrected (fragment) (Box 48, Folder 1422)
    - "Spain," notes, holograph, and draft, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 48, Folder 1423)
    - [Teaching art], typescript and carbon, corrected (fragment) (Box 48, Folder 1424)
    - "Trends in Modern Art," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, [1929] Dec 13 (Box 48, Folder 1425)
      Radio talk on WEAF. Includes clippings.
    - "Unemployment," typescript carbon, corrected, 1930 Dec 5 (Box 48, Folder 1426)
      Radio talk.
    - [Visiting China], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1427)
    - [WPAP radio talk], clipping, 1931 Feb 13 (Box 48, Folder 1428)
    - "Walt Whitman," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1429)
    - "What Has Modern Art Contributed?," typescript carbon, corrected, 1925 Jan 25 (Box 48, Folder 1430)
      At Baltimore Museum of Art. Includes invitation to same lecture at KSD's house, 1925 Mar 25.
    - "Who is Joseph Stella?," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1431)
    - "Why Did Modern Art Come into Existence," typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 48, Folder 1432)
    - [Why painters today paint], holograph, [1942 Feb 20] (Box 48, Folder 1433)
      At Wooster Art Group.
  - NOTES
    - [Art], holograph, in notebook, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1434)
      Includes pencil sketches.
    - "Aso-Neith Cryptogram," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1435)
      In German.
    - [Au-Young, Sum Nung. Lectures on confucianism], holograph, 1928 (Box 49, Folder 1436-1437)
    - [Ball, Frances de Villa. Lectures on modern music], drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, 1925 Jan-Feb (Box 49, Folder 1438)
      Includes program.
    - [Cochran, Aso Neith Neypá. Conversations with], holograph, 1927-32, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1439-1441)
    - "Contents of Portfolios," typescript, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1442)
    - [Duchamp, Marcel. Rotoreliefs], holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, 1936 Jun (Box 49, Folder 1443)
    - [Eilshemius, Louis M. Lecture at the Société Anonyme's museum], typescript, corrected, 1920 Oct 15 (Box 49, Folder 1444)
    - [Expressionism], holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1445)
    - [Faust, Albert Bernhardt. German Element in the United States ], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1446)
    - [Flowers in Art], holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1447)
    - "The History of Painting," holograph, in notebook, 1900 Oct (Box 49, Folder 1448-1449)
    - [History of painting], holograph and typescript, in notebook (Box 49, Folder 1450-1451)
      Some loose pages.
      See also: Oversize, box 118, folder 2806
    - [Kuhn, Franz, editor. The Call of the Mandarin ], typescript carbon (Box 50, Folder 1452)
    - "List of Those Invited to be the First Ten Patrons for the Clinic," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1453)
    - "Materials for an Article by Mr. Scholz for the China Weekly Review and also the Chinese Shun Pao ," typescript carbon, corrected, 1925 May 21 (Box 50, Folder 1454)
    - [Nature and art], holograph (Box 50, Folder 1455)
    - "Notes Taken on Manly Hall's Lecture," typescript and carbon, corrected, 1942 Dec 2 (Box 50, Folder 1456)
    - [Painting, class notes], typescript, 1903-04, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1457)
    - [Paintings], holograph and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 50, Folder 1458)
    - [People KSD has met], typescript, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1459)
    - [Pequeno, Pedro P.]
      - [Index to class notes], holograph, 1944 (Box 51, Folder 1460)
      - [Classes], holograph and typescript, 1921-36 (Box 51, Folder 1461-1471)
    - [Pequeno, Pedro P.]. [Classes], holograph and typescript (cont.), 1936-43, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1472-1482)
    - [Pequeno, Pedro P.]. [Classes], holograph and typescript (Box 53, Folder 1483-1484)
    - "Pictures of Today and Tomorrow," holograph (Box 53, Folder 1485)
    - [Shawn, Ted. Lecture on Delsarte], typescript (Box 53, Folder 1486)
    - [Symbolism in art], holograph and typescript (Box 53, Folder 1487)
    - "Technique in Painting," holograph, in notebook, 1912 (Box 53, Folder 1488)
      Talk with Van Meeren, Florence, 1912 Mar-Apr.
    - [Travel plans], holograph, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1489)
    - [Unidentified], holograph and typescript (Box 53, Folder 1490)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - Autobiography
      - "As It May Have Been," holograph, 1951 (Box 54, Folder 1491)
        Notebook and loose notes.
    - Plays
      - "The Black Pearls," typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 54, Folder 1492)
      - "Lizzie Twitch's Adventures in Art," drafts, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 54, Folder 1493)
    - Poems
      - [Children's songs, transcribed in German by KSD], holograph, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1494)
      - "The Flying Dutchman," drafts, holograph and typescript
      - [God speaks through the beauty...], drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected
      - "A Prayer for Peace," typescript, n.d.
    - Short Stories
      - "Le Medecin de Brai ou le villain devenu medecin"
        See also: Box 17, folders 506-507
        See also: Box 20 folder 591
        - Drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 54, Folder 1495)
        - Pencil drawings, paper and tissue (Box 54, Folder 1496)
      - "The Singing Heart," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1497)
      - "What Was It?," notes, holograph and draft, typescript, corrected, 1920 Oct 13 (Box 54, Folder 1498)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Albers, Josef
      - "Art as Experience," printed version, 1935 Oct (Box 55, Folder 1499)
      - "The Democratizing of the Economic Life of Germany Since the November Revolution of 1918," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1500)
    - Arp, Jean. "Souffle," printed work, with woodblock print, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1501)
    - [Ball, Frances de Villa]. "An Open Letter," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 55, Folder 1502)
    - Beveridge, Ray. "Translated Extracts from the Memoirs of," typescript and carbon (Box 55, Folder 1503)
    - Blanshard, Frances Margaret Bradshaw. "A Memorable Stage in the History of American Art: Katherine S. Dreier and the Société Anonyme," typescript, corrected
      See: Box 4, folder 124
    - Brinton, Christian
      - "Catalogue," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1504)
      - "Modernism in Art," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1505)
    - Burliuk, David
      - [Text for 1933 Dreier exhibition catalog at Academy of Allied Arts], typescript, corrected, 1933 Sep (Box 55, Folder 1506)
      - "A Revelation in Simplicity," drafts, holograph, corrected and typescript (Box 55, Folder 1507)
        Lecture at Brooklyn Museum, 1926 Dec 11.
      - [Review of Modern Russian Art by Louis Lozowick], 1925
        See: Oversize, box 129, folder 2873
    - [Chang, Ziang-ling]
      - "American Audiences," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 55, Folder 1508)
      - "American Characteristics," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1509)
      - "American Women," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1510)
      - "China on Broadway," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 55, Folder 1511)
      - "Chinese Students," drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1512)
      - "Intermarriage," drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1513)
      - "Religion," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1514)
      - "Tong Wars," drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1515)
    - Cheatham, Kitty
      - "America Acknowledges Spiritual Debt to Sweden, in Honoring Crown Prince Gustaf Adolf and Crown Princess Louise," printed version of radio talk, 1926 May 28
        See: Oversize, box 118, folder 2807
      - "Wagner's Consecrational Play and Its Good Friday Music," printed version, New York Herald Tribune, 1938 Apr 10 (Box 55, Folder 1516)
    - Conrow, Wilford Seymour
      - "Additional Notes on Bodily Symmetry," typescript mimeograph, 1935 Aug 21 (Box 55, Folder 1517)
      - "Notes on Portrait Painting," typescript carbon, 1935 May 2 (Box 55, Folder 1518)
      - "The Pentagon Pose," typescript mimeograph, 1935 Jul (Box 55, Folder 1519)
      - "Ratios of Bodily Symmetry with Special Reference to the Pentagon Pose, and the Effect of Respiration," typescript mimeograph (Box 55, Folder 1520)
        With William Churchill and Gustavus A. Eisen for 7th International Art Congress, 1935 Aug 10.
    - Darnton, Maida C. "In My End Is My Beginning," typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 55, Folder 1521)
    - Davies, Arthur B. "Foreword" [to Personal Recollections of Vincent van Gogh ], typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1522)
    - Detwiller, Frederick K.
      - "An American Monument," typescript carbon, 1926 Jan 24 (Box 55, Folder 1523)
      - "Art and Religion," typescript mimeograph, 1925 Mar (Box 55, Folder 1524)
      - "Description of Paintings of the Eclipse," typescript mimeograph, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1525)
      - "Fair Play for Art Exhibitions," typescript mimeograph, 1930 May (Box 55, Folder 1526)
      - "Four and One-Half Acres of Evergreens," typescript carbon, 1924 Jan (Box 55, Folder 1527)
      - "The Jury and Man," typescript mimeograph, 1927 (Box 55, Folder 1528)
      - "The Shaft of Light," typescript mimeograph, 1929 (Box 55, Folder 1529)
    - Doesburg, Nelly van. "Dutch Christmas; French Christmas," typescript and holograph (Box 55, Folder 1530)
    - Dreier, Dorothea A. "Walter Shirlaw"
      Begins: "Among the artists whose works..."
      - Drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1531)
    - Dreier, Dorothea A. "Walter Shirlaw"
      Begins: "Walter Shirlaw was born in Paisley..."
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1532)
      - Typescript mimeograph, n.d.
      - Printed version, Art in America, 1919 Aug
      - Mockup of brochure, n.d.
    - Dreier, Mary E. "Barbara Richards," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1533-1536)
    - Duchamp, Marcel. From the Green Box. Advertisement, n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 118, folder 2808
    - Dunn, Richard. "An American Country Museum of Art," typescript and carbon
      See: Box 11, folder 332
    - Einstein, Karl. "Fernand Léger," holograph, corrected, 1925 Jul (Box 56, Folder 1537)
      In hand of Fernand Léger.
    - Fox, William Henry. "Foreword" [to catalog for Brooklyn Museum. "Exhibition of Paintings and Drawings by the Late Walter Shirlaw and a Group of His Pupils," 1929 Dec 2-1930 Jan 2], typescript carbon, corrected (Box 56, Folder 1538)
      Corrections by KSD.
    - Frank, Waldo David. "Suggested Reading List for Course on Modern Art," typescript mimeograph, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1539)
    - Gabo, Naum. "A Retrospective View of Constructive Art," drafts, typescript and carbon, 1948 Mar 19 (Box 56, Folder 1540)
      Early title: "On Constructive Realism." Lecture at Yale University. Includes lecture announcement.
    - George, George L. "Vladimir Shwab," typescript, n.d.
      See: Box 13, folder 393